For nearly four years,
I took personal training sessions in a
budget gym in
Bracknell, and I loved it,
and I thought that my career had peaked.
And if I'm completely honest with you,
I 100% in my mind thought
that by the time I
was 40, 45,
I would still be doing personal training
sessions, just maybe not so
many of them,
and I would have super wealthy clients.
But I'll let you in on a little secret.
Today, I'm going to record this video.
I'm going to give you four things that
are going to revolutionize the way you see
what we call business.
It's not really business.
It's personal brand
and tactics so you can make more money.
But anyway,
then the second I finish talking,
I'm going to go train jujitsu.
He's going to edit the video,
he's going to throw it on YouTube,
and over the next
three, six, nine days,
I'm going to make thousands of dollars of
revenue from this
very video. So why am I saying this?
Am I showing off? No.
The very tactics I'm about to explain to
you are things that you can implement into
your business. I now, 10 years later,
don't do personal training sessions.
Operate a business
that doesn't need me to be in it.
They say in business,
you either have a puppy or a baby.
With a puppy, no matter how old it gets,
you still got to look after it and clean
up its shit. With a baby, yeah,
it needs a lot of your time and energy
and effort
in the onset,
but then soon it'll take care of itself,
and it'll maybe wipe your
ass one day when you're too old.
Bit of a side tangent.
I have a deal with my dad.
I said,
"If I ever make it to a point in life
that I can't take a shit on my
own without wiping my ass,
ask my dad to end it for me." And he goes,
"Son, if you
do the same for me,
we have a deal." Where were we?
Let's look into stage one, content.
I work with hundreds, actually,
thousands of creators, some of which
are personal trainers, some are physios,
some are golf instructors.
The majority of the people I work with,
in some form, sell their time for
money. One hour costs this. And that
was me for a very long time, and I
thought the only lever
that I could pull on
was to increase my hourly rate.
I never saw outside the four walls in
which I operated in.
And in fact,
I only put videos on social media so
that my paid clients could go
somewhere to learn something,
so I didn't have to repeat myself,
which is a great
place for you to start with the content.
Whether you're a divorce lawyer,
golf instructor, or a jujitsu coach, if we
can see content in the onset as just a
place to not have to repeat ourselves,
that
means when people ask us questions,
we can send them somewhere. Brilliant.
Great.
The second strategy we want to use for
content is that by doing so, people that
don't know us are going to see it.
And it's very important
that you optimize your
pieces of content, not for people
that follow you, for people
that have never seen
you before. And this
is the best way to put it.
Cold audiences hate you by default.
They don't want to see your face.
They don't like it
when your face gets too close
to the camera.
They dislike you.
And they're going to give you about three
to five seconds to take
you from, "I hate your face. Okay,
keep talking." But at that
point, they still don't like you.
And it's your job
and opportunity in every piece
of content to not even win them over,
but for them to admit that you're slightly
bearable. Because then
if they watch enough of the video,
they'll be served your
next. And in the next one,
they're going to go, "There's
that dickhead who had a
pretty good point in their last video."
They give you a bit more of an
opportunity.
And before you know it, 10 videos in,
"I like this person." Then they will
decide
to follow.
But let me tell you things I don't like.
In content when people have said,
"And drop me a follow
if you..." Don't ask for
follows, you beggy little twat.
Second thing, when you say, "And if you
stick around till the end of the video,"
don't do that. It's annoying.
Three, when you try and infer
and insinuate.
"One thing I do with my clients. Oh,
one of my clients called me the other
day." It's very obvious at this point
that the piece of content that you're
creating is about establishing yourself as
someone that has clients, and it's just
not a good look.
And the last point on content
is everything you create is about
them.
So when you're a pleb coming out the
kitchen, "Here's the breakfast that I
eat every day so I can stay in shape as a
personal trainer." Don't
fucking care. Don't fucking care.
You could've done the exact same thing you
bellend.
You could've put a top on
and come round and gone,
"If you're someone that's
looking to lose weight
and you want something that's easy to
create, that's going
to be good for your macros,
that you can have every morning
that could contribute
to you changing your composition for the
better, I recommend this breakfast because
I've had it every day
and I still haven't got bored of it." It's
the same
breakfast. It's the same thing.
Thank God you put your top on.
The video is about them.
It's about helping them.
No one in social media cares about you.
And the better you can understand that,
paired with the fact that the first time
someone sees you, they hate you,
that's when your content can truly start
to make
progress. Now,
before we move into number two, there
is a link in the description
to my content creation course. It's $99.
It's fantastic.
Some people say it's too good and
that I should be charging more,
and I agree.
But let's get into number two,
the data conundrum.
Never called it that before,
but we're calling it that today.
All right, Declan, the data conundrum.
I fucked up this weekend.
I was doing a YouTube live stream
that I promoted.
Halfway through,
the connection dropped out.
It just cut out.
YouTube maybe was doing me dirty
or maybe my dog was chewing on the wires
near the... I don't know.
I had to scramble around,
quickly do the live
on Instagram. It was a complete fuck up.
But it was okay. Do you know why?
Because before doing that live,
I got everyone's email address.
I ran signups.
I ran paid ads. I then,
before the live stream,
emailed everyone saying, "Hey,
guys,
I'm going to be jumping on in a second.
Click this link." They all jumped on.
So when the live stream fucked up,
I lost some of them,
and that's completely fine.
But it was okay because after
that live stream,
I sent them all an email with
an offer to a service that I
was trying to sell them.
The true tragedy would've been
if I'd never taken people's data in the
onset.
Similarly to if you
were on a night out
and you met the love of your life,
potentially. Don't know about you.
When you were younger,
did you ever swipe on Hinge
and then you would accidentally
say no to someone?
Or you would swipe past too quickly
and then flash
before your mind and you go,
"That could've been my future wife." Do
you ever do
that? Never
used Tinder in my life. Sure.
Of course you haven't.
This fucker is so young.
I said to him the other day, "Two minutes
Turkish." He goes, "Don't get it." I
was like, "Snatch." He goes,
"It's before I
was born." I was like, "Shut up,
you dickhead." Snatch was in 2000
and you were born in 2001?
I nearly fucking fired the cunt.
Best not say cunt.
I nearly best fired the twat. Anyway,
data, data, data.
When using social media
and putting out the helpful content,
stage two, you've got
to see yourself like a farmer.
You've got to sprinkle the seeds,
plant them in the
ground. And you've got to wait.
It could take three, six, nine months.
These farmers will wait nine months to
harvest the crops.
And when you harvest the crops,
you want data.
And when you're harvesting,
you might lose some followers.
That's okay.
But at the end of the day,
we need their data so we can reach out to
them direct in
case the YouTube live stream goes down,
in case TikTok gets banned in your
country,
whatever it is. So
when you're moving down,
plant the seeds with content, you
harvest the crops for data.
Cannot stress this enough.
Which is going to take us into number
three.
And I know I can seem like a broken
record.
But if you guys were fucking doing this,
you'd be busy onboarding new clients and
not watching this video. Email marketing.
2014, people thought this was old school.
Let me tell you this. It still spanks.
I have not done one single call to action,
not done one sale,
nothing. I'll show you. I'm not scared
$136,000 for the last four weeks, US.
The only way I've sold to people
is through emails.
Now, the biggest problem that people find,
especially fitness people, I hate to
have a go at you, I just know you well.
"Sign up to my emails
and I'll give you fitness tips." No,
thanks.
"I'll give you insights to fitness." No,
"I will help you be in the best shape of
your life." Cheers,
ChatGPT. From Wish.
Give people something they want.
For golf. I don't play golf. "This
is my 19-stage formula that's going
to revolutionize the way
that you chip." Your title could even be,
"Stop
chipping wrong.
Put your email address in here,
and over the next 19 days, we're
going to revolutionize how you see,
approach, and execute..."
Is chips even a thing
in golf? I don't know.
You could be a swimming instructor.
"Your front crawl sucks.
Over the next 22 days,
we're going to be doing real-life
practical advice
and technique change that's going to not
only improve the
speed in which you swim
but make it feel more effortless at the
same
time." Wow. Give me another. Declan,
put me on the spot.
Give me a profession
that could use email marketing. Chef.
Okay, I like it.
What's the problem I'm facing?
What's the problem you as a chef...
What's the solution to it? Is it cooking?
Is it meal prep?
No one's buying your cookbook. Okay,
now we need to go deeper.
We can't just say purchase cookbook,
because I don't know what problem the
cookbook
is solving. There is no problem.
No one's problem is, "I haven't got a
cookbook." What is their problem, Declan?
Single dads don't how to cook.
Single dads don't know. Love this.
I'm sure that cooking for the majority of
your life wasn't a problem because there
was a woman in there. Maybe your mother,
then your partner, but for some reason,
you're left in charge of it.
So you need something that's simple,
idiot-proof, and
effective to not only feed you,
nourish you, but help you
get back the feeling of your youth.
Over the next month, each day,
we're going to be talking about
strategies,
devices, things like air fryers,
what type of cooking oils you should use
to not
only enjoy your food again,
not only take charge of your own
nutrition,
but to get yourself looking so good,
your ex wants you back.
Boom. Then deliver the value by email.
Make that an automated process,
because the reason I have so many sales
here is the
videos I've been putting out the last few
days often have call to actions like,
"Hey, link in the description,
get the content course.
Hey, link in the descriptions,
get 30 days of free business advice." Then
people
join that,
and if it revolutionizes their life with
really good information that
comes across on a daily basis,
people eventually buy.
Through my list, day 19 to 21. So even
if you're there thinking that, "I'm
not going to buy this program," they all
say that.
Day 19 to 21, I'll get your brother.
A few golden tips on emails.
Better off leaving them wanting more than
giving them too much.
It's a bit like dating. In the onset,
you're brief.
You're not sending messages too long.
You're not doing too many line breaks.
If we just met on a night out
and you give me a little essay of a text,
I'm
[laughs] not seeing this person again.
Borderline, if you think, "Oh,
they didn't even put that much care
and effort into
that message," I'm interested. Be chill.
Work it in as we go along.
And then if they've still not bought by
day 30, you can talk to them frankly, like
you've been on seven first dates
and they slump out.
You're like, "Yo, where are we at?
We've been on the dates.
Why haven't we been sexing yet?
Why haven't you given me the sticky stuff?
It's been too long." Because
if you do that on the first date,
that's just not
gentlemanly, and it's just inappropriate.
But by date seven, by email 30,
you can be like, "Yo, are we doing
this or what? Get in the bedroom,
join my program." And if they're not
interested, that's fine.
Got to respect their decision.
Now, stage four is a very important one.
I'm going to try and get it done in 60
seconds.
Now,
I know that you've heard a lot of things
about content, data, emails coming
down,
but I would say one of the biggest
tragedies is this.
Let's say for every 100 people
that watch your content,
I think your golden rule
should be getting 20% of their email
addresses.
And as a golden rule, let's do
that on following, not views.
So if you have 1,000 followers,
you should have 200 email addresses.
My math's right? Now, out of that,
I don't really care about open rates.
Everyone's like,
"What open rate should I have?" Well,
it depends on how good your
content is, how you got their data,
whether it was paid, whether it
was organic,
how good your squeeze was,
what method you used to get
that person over the line.
Then there's not just the quality of your
emails, the type of person you're going
after,
because in a business-to-business context,
they might be more incentivized
to read it than a business to consumer,
like fat loss.
Not only that, you know
when you're busy and you go through your
inbox and you mark
emails as read just to make them go away?
That then goes to their email provider as
an open.
So I think the best thing to have a
success rate as is
when someone goes to stage
four.
And then the real ultimate thing of
success we want to care about is them
going to stage five,
which we didn't talk about.
But before we talk about stage five
that I left off on purpose,
let's look into
stage four. A landing page
is not a website.
Everyone seems to think you need to have a
nice little website, and usually up here
it says, "About me, work with us, contact,
location,
FAQs." All the shit you don't want someone
going on.
Then sometimes people put little social
media icons at the bottom. Wait, hold on.
So I got you on social media so
that I could get your data from you,
so I could
then put you into a clever email marketing
campaign, so I could send you to my
landing page,
so then you could click onto my YouTube
and get distracted and be on
YouTube. No.
That sends them the wrong way up the
funnel.
The reason I like a nice landing page,
which you can do on Leadpages, which, yes,
costs $49 a month, but it looks nice.
This is where we convert people to decide
to do business with us.
If you're going on a date,
you don't wear old clothes that smell,
and you don't
wear dirty trainers.
You care about your appearance because it
could be the
difference between you getting laid
or not.
This is the biggest hurdle
that so many people fall down, and
if you really want to
unfuck your business, this
is the place you do it.
Now, title, more important, promise.
Overpromise, then overdeliver.
If you're going to make big claims, cool,
fine,
just deliver on them. That's fine.
Just reading that title should tell me
everything I need to know about what you
do,
how you're going to help me,
and who this program
is for Establish it hard.
Second thing, VSL, video sales letter.
Don't waffle.
"I've worked with clients for many years,
and I'm from Birmingham," and
none of that. Just tell me what it is.
And I don't need to say,
"I'm James Smith." You know.
You just came from my emails.
You just came from my paid ads.
You just came from my socials.
Tell me what it is.
The business mentorship
is where I help people utilize social
media to make more
money.
I don't ask people to put in more time
or more effort.
They're already putting in enough time
and effort.
I just want the existing effort they're
putting in to be used more strategically
so
they can make more money.
I've learned a lot of things operating
businesses over
the last 10 years. I now share
that with people.
Doesn't need to be over-edited,
doesn't need to have subtitles. Raw,
honest.
And here's something
that I've been saying to people recently.
Don't script this.
If you can't sell what it
is you're doing without a script, how
the fuck can your services be worth what
you're charging?
I should be able to wake Declan up with a
bucket of icy water in the middle of the
morning, and he should be able to sit up,
and he should be able to tell me what he
does for a job and why he's of value to
me.
If he can't do that,
people just want to see a video of you as
well.
Makes you look less botty and real.
Underneath,
we mimic what we have in the video.
The golden things that I say you need,
what it is, why they need it,
what they get,
how much it costs, how to pay.
If you do want to do a pricing comparison
box,
fine. One or two offers.
Don't overcomplicate it.
Five, easiest thing, money-back guarantee.
You're going to triple,
quadruple your sales by offering a
money-back guarantee.
If 5% of people take you up on a refund,
you're still better off.
If more than 15% take you up on a refund,
your product isn't good enough.
And the last thing you need
is a buy button. Not Apply Now.
It's not a fucking Soho House membership.
You're going to take on anyone anyway.
Buy. Let me know how to buy.
Some people here then go to a form where
you've
got to give them your name, your details,
your email address.
They've just come from there.
Why would you get them to fill out a form
to tell you
more about them when you've got everything
already?
The next thing you should have from this
person is an email from Stripe or PayPal
saying a new client has been created,
so you can then email them, contact them,
onboard them the best you can,
or have that automated.
Then the frank matter of it
is you send 100 people to this,
a client pops out.
You want 10 clients,
you send 1,000 people.
You want 100 clients,
whatever the maths is on that.
The more people you want to send from
here,
the more people you need on your email
list.
The more people you need on your email
list, the more you put out good
content. And it all trickles down.
And that's what stage five is,
having happy customers.
If you can learn this, you can rinse
and repeat it for any business you want.
Started with personal training, did well.
These are sold out from one email.
We had to take this offline.
Do you know how incompetent
that makes us look?
We had to reserve some stock for people on
subscriptions, but our email marketing
for this did so well it fucked us.
When people buy Noonic, we'll wait
12 days, and we'll email them again.
And we can say in the email, "Ooh,
you're probably out of Noonic by now." I
even
said to the team,
"Let's email people after ten days
and say, 'Chances are,
you've not just had a can a day,
but someone in your household has also had
a can.
So when you're reordering,
don't just order for yourself,
but order for the person
in your house that likes them.'"
When we bring out new products,
we can promote
this to get email addresses to then sell
the cans to.
We can sell the cans to people,
put these in.
If you buy a bundle of the cans,
we'll put these in for free.
Everything goes the same way.
Social media, content awareness.
Email marketing, landing page.
On the landing page,
we talk about the ingredients,
we link the studies,
we talk about the pricing,
we talk about dosage and we talk
about everything.
And the very last link
that I'll put in the description,
short-form content course,
30 days of information that you can steal.
The next one is going to be my landing
page.
And if you click on that,
you can look at the business mentorship,
look at what I
do for a living,
and it's going to tell you exactly all
those things.
You're going to see my VSL, my title,
my promise, my price points, everything.
The stuff I'm talking about
and teaching you, I've rinsed and repeat
for so many businesses.
And the best part of that is this.
I now get to come here, sit with Declan,
have a laugh, make content,
put out this video, and everything
is taken care of for me.
The next thing that I will see of you
is seeing you in the Discord,
welcoming you,
critiquing your content,
and looking at your landing page.
There is a world you live in where you
unfuck your business, you post awesome
content, and clients pop out.
But you're only going to get there
if you get these
bits right.
There's only so many years
that I can keep rinsing
and repeating this.
It's now time for you to do it.
If you want to do it properly,
use the links in the
description. See you later.
If you follow those four things,
you can easily unfuck your business.
And if you feel like there's still more
information that you want to learn,
YouTube's recommended this video of mine.
If you watch this, you could be
that step closer to unfucking your
business, and
maybe even fucking in general,
because it sounds like all my videos
are full of
dating advice.